NIKHIL VENKATESH +91 9742529705 nikhilvenkatesh10@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-venkatesh-a83101142

OBJECTIVE

Highly motivated professional with 1 year+ of experience of providing executive level support. Self-starter with exceptional interpersonal and organizational abilities.

Expertise in production planning, production management, production optimization and supply chain management.

Desire employment as a Supply chain executive in a professional environment that encourages dedication and fruitful hard work, to utilize my organizational as well as administrative abilities.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- PRODUCTION PLANNING
- INVENTORY MGMT.
- TEAM MANAGEMENT

- PROJECT MANAGEMENT
- PROBLEM SOLVING
- INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- SPEND ANALYSIS
- CLIENT HANDLING
- SUPPLY CHAIN

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mirable Health Services, Bangalore (Sep 2019- Present)

Core Business: Develop and manage Diagnostics centers across India

Inventory Planning Executive

- Liaising and negotiating with customers and suppliers
- ➤ All logistics functions-Imports & exports, Inventory/material handling, to make sure warehouse is run efficiently
- Preparation & release of Purchase Orders
- ➤ Co-ordinate with Regional sales Offices/clinicians for product dispatch & other relevant activities.

NIKHIL VENKATESH +91 9742529705 nikhilvenkatesh10@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-venkatesh-a83101142

WHIRLPOOL CORPORATION, Milan (May 2019- Sep 2019)

Core Business: Manufacture of home appliances worldwide - whirlpool.eu Logistics Analyst Trainee

- Analyze the process of awarding contracts to third party logistics companies
- Analyze the spending of the company for procurement of these 3PL'S
- Identifying the deviations of costs from their budget
- > Conducting a spend analysis to study the reasons behind deviation of costs
- > Suggest correctable measures based on the analysis to reduce cost of logistics

GENMOT COILS, Bangalore (November 2017- April 2018)

Core Business: Manufacture of electrical coils for stator and rotors of motors - genmotcoils.com Mechanical Engineer Trainee

- > Lead a group of dedicated workers to produce V.P.I. (VACCUM PRESSURE IMPREGNATED) Coils
- Analyzed and amended day to day problems arising during production of V.P.I. coils
- Managed client engagement regarding production and quality of V.P.I. coils
- Conducted purchasing of materials required for production of coils
- > Maintained quality of V.P.I. coils during production and reduced defects during manufacturing

DOOSAN BOBCAT INDIA PVT. LTD., Bangalore (January 2017 - July 2017)

Manufacture of Air Compressors required for different industrial processes - doosaninfracore.com Project Intern

- Studied and internalized the working of an air compressor
- Analyzed ways to switch regulation system of the air compressor from pneumatic to electronic regulation
- Developed a prototype with a team to control regulation of engine in an air compressor through electronic regulation
- Achieved cost reduction, increasing efficiency of engine by 7% thereby changing regulation system from pneumatic to electronic

Completed an internship in JSW STEEL PLANT BELLARY in January 2016

NIKHIL VENKATESH +91 9742529705 nikhilvenkatesh10@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-venkatesh-a83101142

EDUCATION

PROGRAM	INSTITUTE/UNIVERSITY	YEAR
International Master in Supply Chain and Procurement Management	MIP Politecnico di Milano Business School, Milan	2018-2019
Bachelor's Degree in Mechanical Engineering	Visvesvaraya Technological University, Karnataka	2013-2017
XII	Deeksha Integrated PU College, Bangalore	2011-2013

SKILLS SUMMARY

- > Advanced knowledge of Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook,)
- > SOLID EDGE (advanced)
- > C (advanced)
- > E-Purchasing (Advanced)
- > Excellent Verbal and Written Communication
- Coordination skills

LANGUAGES KNOWN

English: BilingualHindi: Fluent

Kannada: Mother tongueTelugu: Intermediate

> Italian: Beginner

Nationality: Indian

Current address: Bengaluru, India

REFERENCES

References available upon request